Finding aid to the James Parker records, 1924-2005 Archives.Parker.1
The Metropolitan Museum of Art Archives
- Series I. Research, 1912-1997, n.d.; 31.0 Linear feet (72 boxes, 839 folders)
  - Subseries I.A. Card File, 1922-1933, 1943-1950, 1957-1996, n.d.; 25.0 Linear feet (60 boxes, 722 folders)
    - Arms and iconology. Italian. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Arms and iconology. P - S. (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Note: Includes Portuguese. Russian. Scottish.
    - Arms and iconology. S - U. (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Note: Includes Spanish. Swedish. Swiss. U.S.A. Ecclesiastical.
    - Birdcages. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Bronze, gilt. A - D. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Bronze, gilt. English. (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Adam. Anderson, Diederich Nicolaus. Blake, Robert. Blockley, Thomas. Boulton, Matthew. Decaix, Alexis. Elkington. Elsley, Thomas. Garrard. Gascoigne, Edward. Hatfield (Hardman, Garrard, Hart). Jean, Dominique. Pinchbeck, Christopher. Vulliamy, B.L. Wertheimer, Samson. 19th century. Mixed. Contains correspondence from R.S. Whittington, Norman Adams London to Philippe de Montebello, M.M.A. (1983).
    - Bronze, gilt. French. (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Note: gilt bronze is also referred to as silvered bronze, ormolu, g.b., gilt-bronze, metal gilt. Contains correspondence to Robin Campbell, Peebles Island State Park (1983).
    - Bronze, gilt. French. 17th century - Louis XIV. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Bronze, gilt. French. 18th century. (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Note: Contains 1 slide.
    - Bronze, gilt. French. Régence - Louis XV. (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Note: Contains correspondence from Louis See, Ramsay (1963).
    - Bronze, gilt. French. Louis XVI. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Bronze, gilt. French. Empire - Restoration. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Bronze, gilt. French. 19th century. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Bronze, gilt. French. 20th century. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Bronze, gilt. French. Makers. (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Note: Contains correspondence from Preston Remington, M.M.A. to French and Company, Inc. (1931).
    - Bronze, gilt. French. Makers (A - B). (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Note: Includes Adam, Victor. Auguste. Aze. Barbédienne. Bachelier. Bardin. Bazort. Bazil. Besnier. Beurdeley, A.A. Biennais. Le Blanc. Boquet. Boucher, Jullien. Boudet. Bouillerot, J. Buraux, Pierre. Contains correspondence to Mrs. J.P. Brennan (1980).
    - Bronze, gilt. French. Makers (Ca). (Box 2, Folder 13)
      Note: Includes Caffieri. Cahier. Caignard. Caille et Cie. Canieure. Carpentier, Pierre Francois. Carrier-Belleuse. Cartellier. Cauvet. Cavais.
    - Bronze, gilt. French. Makers (Ch - Cu). (Box 2, Folder 14)
      Note: Includes Chaine. Charié. Charpentier. Chaumont. Choíselat. Christofle. Confesseur, Jacques. Cressent. Crozatier. Cumberworth, C.
    - Bronze, gilt. French. Makers (D). (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Daguerre. Dambière. Danchot. Dasson. Decoix. Delafontaine. Denière et Matelin. Deusnier. Deverberie. Dewez. Disnematin. Dizy. Doussamy. Dumont. Dunand. Duplessis. Duterme. Duverger. Duvivier.
    - Bronze, gilt. French. Makers (E - F). (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Ervieux. l'éveillé. Falize. Felois. Feuchère. Fichet. Forestier. Forty. Fossey. Froment-Meurice. Fuzillier.
    - Bronze, gilt. French. Makers (G - Gon). (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Gagneau. Galle. Gallien. Gambier, J.R. Geoffroy, Pierre. Germain. Gobert. Godille. Gonon.
    - Bronze, gilt. French. Makers (Gou - Gu). (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes Gouthière. Grimpelle, Ch. Guerin, P.E. Guinand, Jacques.
    - Bronze, gilt. French. Makers (H - L). (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Habert (See also: Hubert), Laurent. Hazard. Heban. Hector. Henry, Nicolas. Hervieu. Jeannest, Louis-Francois. Ladoireau. Lafond. Laguessè. Lebeuf, Jean-Louis. Leclair, J.B. Ledure, Victor. Lelièvre. Leloutre. Lemaire, P. Lemorchand. Lemerle (1869+). Lerman, S. Léveillé.
    - Bronze, gilt. French. Makers (M - O). (Box 3, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes Le Macque. Macque, Christophe de la. Magnien. Mahault. Manière. Marchand, Pierre. Mariette, Jean-Pierre. Martincourt. Mellet. Message, Léon. Michallon, Claude. Millet. Mondon. Moreau. Morel. Le Nègre. Noel, M.F. Oblet, F.B. Osmond. Contains correspondence with Gerard Arpin (1979).
    - Bronze, gilt. French. Makers (P). (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Paillard. Pajot, A.P. Parguez. Pessoneaux and Colomb. Picard, H. Piret, Jules. Pitoin. Prévost. Prieur. Le Prince. Contains correspondence with Gerard Arpin (1979) and from Jayne Wrightsman (n.d.).
    - Bronze, gilt. French. Makers (R). (Box 3, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Rabiat. Rachette. Raimond (see also: Rémond). Raingo Frères (see also: Horology). Ravrio. Renard, Jacques. Ricard, H. Robbe. Roettiers. Romain, Pierre Etienne. Le Roy. Roye, E.
    - Bronze, gilt. French. Makers (S). (Box 3, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes Saint-Germain. Satray. Secretant. Servont, M.G. Sévin, Louis-Constant. Solon. Sormani. Soyeretingé. Susse Frères. Contains correspondence from Jean-Dominique Augarde (1983) and to Robert V. Bayer, Vandervelden (1965).
    - Bronze, gilt. French. Makers (Thomire). (Box 3, Folder 10)
      Note: Thomire, Pierre-Philippe, 1751-1843. Includes Thomire in Demidov (San Donato) Collection. Contains correspondence from David H. Cohen, J. Paul Getty Museum (1990) and Gerald F. Abbott to David Cohen (1980?).
    - Bronze, gilt. French. Makers (T - W). (Box 3, Folder 11)
      Note: Includes Thierard, F.C. Toulouse, Jean-Claude. Turpin, Joseph-Noel. Varins. Vassé. Vassou. De Verberie. Vian, B. Vion. Vittoz. Mixed.
    - Bronze, gilt. German. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Bronze, gilt. Italian. (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Makers.
    - Bronze, gilt. Marks. (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Note: Contains a list of Crowned-C marks on Gilt Bronze Objects in M.M.A.'s Collection (2/8/1980). Contains correspondence from F.J.B. Watson (1968) and Gillian Wilson, J. Paul Getty Museum (1971).
    - Bronze, gilt. P - U. (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Portuguese. Russian. Spanish. Swedish. U.S.A.See also: Series I. Research / Series I.A. Card Files / f. Ironwork. Spanish.See also: Series I. Research / Subseries I.B. General / f. P.E. Guerin, Inc.See also: Series I. Research / Subseries I.A. Card File / f. Bronze, Gilt. French. Makers.
    - Bronze, silvered. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Carriages and sleds. A - D. (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Austrian. Dutch. Contains correspondence from Jayne Barbee (1977).See also: Series I. Research / Suberies I.A. Card File / f. Chairs, sedan.
    - Carriages and sleds. English. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Carriages and sleds. French. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Carriages and sleds. G - I. (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes German. Italian. Contains correspondence from Amedeo de Franchis, NATO (1984).
    - Carriages and sleds. P - S. (Box 4, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes Portuguese. Russian. Scandinavian. Spanish.
    - Ceramics. A. (Box 4, Folder 10)
      Note: Includes Austrian.
    - Ceramics. Chinese (1 of 2). (Box 4, Folder 11)
      Note: Includes Clocks. Fish.
    - Ceramics. Chinese (2 of 2). (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Ceramics. D. (Box 4, Folder 13)
      Note: Includes Danish. Dutch.
    - Ceramics. English. (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Porcelain chimneypieces. Porcelain clocks. Porcelain furniture. Porcelain lighting. Porcelain sculpture. Vases. Mixed. Contains correspondence from Dorothy Miner, The Walters Art Gallery to Jessie McNab, M.M.A. (1959) and to Mr. Nickerson, Mallet (1984).
    - Ceramics. French (1 of 7). (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Ceramics. French (2 of 7). (Box 5, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Porcelain clocks.
    - Ceramics. French (3 of 7). (Box 5, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes Sèvres. Sèvres imitators. Porcelain lighting.
    - Ceramics. French (4 of 7). (Box 5, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Furniture porcelain plaques. Contains description of "Table des Palais Imperiaux puis des Chateaux Royaux."
    - Ceramics. French (5 of 7). (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes Furniture porcelain plaques. Contains correspondence from William Denton, Estates by Denton (1968) and Gillian Wilson, J. Paul Getty Museum (1980).
    - Ceramics. French (6 of 7). (Box 5, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Biscuit de Sèvres. Porcelain service.
    - Ceramics. French (7 of 7). (Box 5, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Porcelain vases. Mixed. Contains 1 slide.
    - Ceramics. German (1 of 2). (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Ceramics. German (2 of 2). (Box 6, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Porcelain furniture. Porcelain inkstands. Porcelain lighting. Porcelain vases. Mixed.
    - Ceramics. Gr - W. (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Greek. Irish. Italian. Japanese. Portuguese. Russian. Spanish. Swedish. Swiss. U.S.A. Welsh.
    - Chairs, sedan. A - E. (Box 6, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes Austrian. English.
    - Chairs, sedan. F - I. (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes French. German. Italian. Contains correspondence from Alvar Gonzalez Palacios (1977).
    - Chairs, sedan. P - S. (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes Portuguese. Spanish.
    - Chimneys. A - E. (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Austrian. Belgian. Dutch. English.
    - Chimneys. Andirons. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Chimneys. Chimney furniture. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Chimneys. Chimneypieces (1 of 6). (Box 6, Folder 10)
      See also: Series I. Research / Subseries I.A. Card File / f. Chimneys. French. Chimneypieces.
    - Chimneys. Chimneypieces (2 of 6). (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Chimneys. Chimneypieces (3 of 6). (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Chimneys. Chimneypieces (4 of 6). (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Chimneys. Chimneypieces (5 of 6). (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Chimneys. Chimneypieces (6 of 6). (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Chimneys. Chimneypieces. Makers. (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Note: Includes Chimney boards.
    - Chimneys. Fire screens. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Chimneys. French. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Chimney furniture and firebacks. Devants de cheminée. Garnitures de cheminée.
    - Chimneys. French. Andirons. (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Pre-Louis XIV.
    - Chimneys. French. Andirons. Louis XIV. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Chimneys. French. Andirons. Régence. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Chimneys. French. Andirons. Louis XV (1 of 4). (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Chimneys. French. Andirons. Louis XV (2 of 4). (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Chimneys. French. Andirons. Louis XV (3 of 4). (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Chimneys. French. Andirons. Louis XV (4 of 4). (Box 7, Folder 9)
      Note: Contains correspondence from Sarah Medlam, Bowes Museum (1985).
    - Chimneys. French. Andirons. Louis XVI (1 of 6). (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Chimneys. French. Andirons. Louis XVI (2 of 6). (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Chimneys. French. Andirons. Louis XVI (3 of 6). (Box 7, Folder 12)
      Note: Contains correspondence from French and Co. (signature of writer illegible) to Preston Remington (1929).
    - Chimneys. French. Andirons. Louis XVI (4 of 6). (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Chimneys. French. Andirons. Louis XVI (5 of 6). (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Chimneys. French. Andirons. Louis XVI (6 of 6). (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Chimneys. French. Andirons. Empire. (Box 7, Folder 16)
      Note: Contains correspondence from Gerald F. Abbott to David H. Cohen, J. Paul Getty Museum (1980)
    - Chimneys. French. Andirons. Restoration, Second Empire. (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Chimneys. French. Chimneypieces. Pre-17th century - Louis XIV. (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Chimneys. French. Chimneypieces. Régence - Louis XV. (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Chimneys. French. Chimneypieces. Louis XVI. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Chimneys. French. Chimneypieces. Empire, 19th century. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Chimneys. French. Fire screens. Louis XIV, Régence. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Chimneys. French. Fire screens. Louis XV. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Chimneys. French. Fire screens. Louis XVI. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Chimneys. French. Fire screens. Empire, 19th century. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Chimneys. French. Paravents. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Chimneys. G - Ir. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Chimneys. Italian. (Box 8, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes Andirons. Chimneypieces. Chimney furniture.
    - Chimneys. R - U. (Box 8, Folder 10)
      Note: Includes Russian. Spanish. Swedish. U.S.A.
    - Collections. A. (Box 8, Folder 11)
      Note: Includes Austrian. Australian. Contains correspondence to Marian Earnest (1992).
    - Collection. B - E. (Box 8, Folder 12)
      Note: Includes Belgian. Czechoslovakian. Danish. Dutch. Egyptian. Filipino (out of sequence). Excludes English.
    - Collections. English (A). (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Collections. English (B). (Box 8, Folder 14)
      Note: Contains correspondence with Henry Hawley, Cleveland Museum of Art (1990).
    - Collections. English (C). (Box 8, Folder 15)
      Contains correspondence from Eileen Harris (1991).
    - Collections. English (D). (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Collections. English (E - F). (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Collections. English (G). (Box 9, Folder 3)
      Note: Contains a list of Percival D. Griffiths' objects in M.M.A.'s collection (9/4/1992).
    - Collections. English (H). (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Collections. English (I - L). (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Note: Contains correspondence from H.G. Belsey, The Bowood Estates (1979) and to John Goldsmith Phillips, M.M.A. (1958).
    - Collections. English (M). (Box 9, Folder 6)
      Note: Contains correspondence to R.S. Whittington, Norman Adams, Ltd. (1983).
    - Collections. English (N - P). (Box 9, Folder 7)
      Note: Contains correspondence from Catherine Norman (1990).
    - Collections. English (R). (Box 9, Folder 8)
      Note: Contains correspondence to P.J. Rushbrooke (1978).
    - Collections. English (S). (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Collections. English (T - V). (Box 9, Folder 10)
      Note: Contains correspondence from Lorna Haycock, Wiltshire Archaeological and Natural History Society (1996).
    - Collections. English (W - Z). (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Collections. French (A). (Box 10, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Comte d'Artois. Duc d'Aumale. Duc d'Aumont. Contains correspondence from Pierre Verlet (1985).
    - Collections. French (B - Ba). (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Madame du Barry.
    - Collections. French (Be). (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Beauharnais.
    - Collections. French (Bi - Bonn). (Box 10, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes Bonapartes. Contains correspondence from Simon de Pury, Sotheby's Europe (1989).
    - Collections. French (Bor - Boy). (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Boucher.
    - Collections. French (Br - Bu). (Box 10, Folder 6)
      Note: Contains correspondence from Victor Carlson, Baltimore Museum of Art (1979).
    - Collections. French (Ca). (Box 10, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Castellane. Contains correspondence to Christian Baulez, Musée National du Château de Versailles (1984).
    - Collections. French (Ch). (Box 10, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Choiseul.
    - Collections. French (Cl - Co). (Box 10, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes Condé. Contains correspondence from Richard A. Bourne (1974).
    - Collections. French (Cr - Cy). (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Collections. French (Da). (Box 10, Folder 11)
      Note: Includes Dauphin.
    - Collections. French (De - Do). (Box 10, Folder 12)
      Note: Includes Diderot.
    - Collections. French (Dr - Du). (Box 10, Folder 13)
      Note: Includes Duthé.
    - Collections. French (E). (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Collections. French (F). (Box 11, Folder 1)
      Note: Contains correspondence from Jean Feray, Ministere de la Culture et de la Communication (1983).
    - Collections. French (G). (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Note: Contains correspondence from Deborah L. Krohn, M.M.A. (1996) and René Huyghe, Musée Jacquemart-André (1987).
    - Collections. French (H). (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Collections. French (I - K). (Box 11, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes Josephine.
    - Collections. French (L - Lop). (Box 11, Folder 5)
      Note: Contains correspondence from Preston Remington, M.M.A. to Moon Carroll (1925).
    - Collections. French (Louis XIII). (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Collections. French (Louis XIV). (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Collections. French (Louis XV). (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Collections. French (Louis XVI). (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Collections. French (Louis XVII). (Box 11, Folder 10)
      See also: Series I. Research / Subseries I.A. Card File / f. Collections. French [O] for Louis-Philippe.
    - Collections. French (Louise - Luy). (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Collections. French (M - Man). (Box 11, Folder 12)
      See also: Series I. Research / Subseries I.C. Collections / f. French [O] for Queen Marie-Amélie.
    - Collections. French (Marie-Antoinette). (Box 11, Folder 13)
      Note: Marie Antoinette, Queen, consort of Louis XVI, King of France, 1755-1793.
    - Collections. French (Marie-Josephe de Saxe - Marie-Leczinska). (Box 11, Folder 14)
      Note: Marie-Josèphe, de Saxe, 1731-1767. Marie Leszczynska, Queen, consort of Louis XV, King of France, 1703-1768.
    - Collections. French (Marie-Louise). (Box 11, Folder 15)
      Note: Marie Louise, Empress, consort of Napoleon I, Emperor of the French, 1791-1847.
    - Collections. French (Mariette - Maz). (Box 11, Folder 16)
      Note: Includes Mazarin. Contains correspondence from Stéphane Boudin, Jansen to James J. Rorimer, M.M.A. (1957).
    - Collections. French (Me - Mu). (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Note: Contains correspondence to Jean D. King (1986).
    - Collections. French (N). (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Napoleon I - III.
    - Collections. French (O). (Box 12, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Orléans (Gaston, General, Monsieur, Régent, Father, Egalité, King, 19th - 20th centuries, Comte de Paris). Contains correspondence from Ann Marie Murphy, American Security Bank (1986).
    - Collections. French (P - Pol). (Box 12, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes Penthièvre. Contains correspondence with Mlle. Nathalie Müller (1989). Contains 1 slide.
    - Collections. French (Pompadour). (Box 12, Folder 5)
      Note: Pompadour, Jeanne Antoinette Poisson, marquise de, 1721- 1764. Includes portraits of.
    - Collections. French (Pon - Q). (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Collections. French (R - Ri). (Box 12, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Richelieu.
    - Collections. French (Ro). (Box 12, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Rohan. Rothschild. Contains correspondence from Kunsthistoriches Museum (signature of writer illegible) to Preston Remington, M.M.A. (1929) and from the secretary of Baron Guy de Rothschild to Edith A. Standen, M.M.A. (1975).
    - Collections. French (S). (Box 12, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes Stanislas Leczinski. Contains correspondence with Lucia M. Scalisi, Victoria and Albert Museum (1985).See also: Series I. Research / Subseries I.A. Card File / f. Collections. [Polish] for Stanislas Leczinski.
    - Collections. French (T). (Box 12, Folder 10)
      Note: Includes Talleyrand. Contains correspondence from Victoire Taittinger Gardner to Philippe de Montebello, M.M.A. (1987) and from Michèle Bordier-Nikitine, Musées du Mans (1986).
    - Collections. French (U - Z). (Box 12, Folder 11)
      Note: Includes Vivant Denon. Contains correspondence from J.L. Picard, transcribed by Henry Sorensen (1970).
    - Collections. German. (Box 13, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Frederick II of Prussia. Contains correspondence with Hermann Bresinsky (1989).
    - Collections. G - Ir. (Box 13, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Greek. Hungarian. Indian. Irish.
    - Collections. Italian (A - F). (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Collections. Italian (G - Z). (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Collections. L. (Box 13, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Liechtenstein. Luxembourg.
    - Collections. M - Pol. (Box 13, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes Mexican. Norwegian. Polish.
    - Collections. Portuguese. (Box 13, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Gulbenkian. Patiño-Ortiz. Espirito Santo Silva.
    - Collections. Russian. (Box 13, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Alexander. Catherine the Great. Demidoff. Elizabeth. Marie-Feodorovna. Du Nord. Paul I. Peter the Great. Romanovs. Stroganoff.
    - Collections. Scottish. (Box 13, Folder 9)
      See also: Series I. Research / Subseries I.A. Card File / f. Collections. English.
    - Collections. South American. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Collections. Spanish. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Collections. Sw - T. (Box 13, Folder 12)
      Note: Includes Swedish. Swiss. Turkish. Yugoslavian (out of sequence). Contains correspondence from Provence Antiques, Inc. (1984).
    - Collections. U.S.A. (A). (Box 14, Folder 1)
      Note: Contains memorandum to James J. Rorimer, M.M.A. (1960) and from Madeleine Beaufort-Fidell (1978).
    - Collections. U.S.A. (B). (Box 14, Folder 2)
      Note: Contains correspondence to Robert Tyler Davis, French and Company, Inc. (1963) and Jean Gabriel Martin (1993).
    - Collections. U.S.A. (C). (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Collections. U.S.A. (D). (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Collections. U.S.A. (E - F). (Box 14, Folder 5)
      Note: Contains correspondence with Ellen M. Rosenthal, Clayton (1987).
    - Collections. U.S.A. (G). (Box 14, Folder 6)
      Note: Contains correspondence from David H. Cohen, J. Paul Getty Center for the History of Art and the Humanities (1985) and S. Jon Gerstenfeld (1978).
    - Collections. U.S.A. (H). (Box 14, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Hearst. Contains memorandum to Penelope Bardel, M.M.A. (1976) and correspondence from Richard G. Hewitt, Wormser, Kiely, Alessandroni, Hyde and McCann (1987).
    - Collections. U.S.A. (I - J). (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Collections. U.S.A. (K). (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Collections. U.S.A. (L). (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Linsky. Contains memorandum from Lowery S. Sims, M.M.A. (1984), correspondence from Margaret S. Moore, Sterling and Francine Clark Art Institute (1989) and to Paul L. Kohns (1972).
    - Collections. U.S.A. (M). (Box 15, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Morgan. Contains correspondence to Chodna Devitt (1988), from Mary Pikrallidas, Ash Lawn (1983), from Pauline G. King, Mary Washington College (1977), from Theodore Dell (1995), from P. Randolph Morris (1930), from D.W. Wright, Morgan Library to Jessie McNab, M.M.A. (1994), from Jean-Marie Van Isacker to William Rieder, M.M.A. (1991) and from Clare Le Corbeiller, M.M.A. (1976).
    - Collections. U.S.A. (N - O). (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Collections. U.S.A. (P - Q). (Box 15, Folder 4)
      Note: Contains correspondence from Eleanor Wayne Macpherson to Joseph Downs (1945).
    - Collections. U.S.A. (R). (Box 15, Folder 5)
      Note: Contains correspondence from Douglas Hyland, Birmingham Museum of Art (1989).
    - Collections. U.S.A. (S). (Box 15, Folder 6)
      Note: Contains correspondence from Neil Sellin (1987), Bradford Garnett, Douglas Elliman (1992), Peter Sharp (1987) and a memorandum to Olga Raggio, M.M.A. (1990).
    - Collections. U.S.A. (T - V). (Box 15, Folder 7)
      Note: Contains correspondence from Douglas Dillon, M.M.A. to Samuel Untermyer (1980) and from Alan Hartman, Hartman Trading Corp. (1968).
    - Collections. U.S.A. (W - Wh). (Box 15, Folder 8)
      Note: Contains correspondence to John N. Stephen (1986).
    - Collections. U.S.A. (Wi - Wu). (Box 15, Folder 9)
      Note: Contains correspondence from Francis Henry Taylor, M.M.A. to John Wise (1943).
    - Collections. U.S.A. (Y - Z). (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Costume. (Box 16, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes English. French. Italian. Scottish.
    - Currency. (Box 16, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes English. French. Italian. Spanish.
    - Dealers. (Box 16, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Belgian. Dutch.
    - Dealers. English. (Box 16, Folder 4)
      Note: Contains correspondence from A.S. Ciechanowiecki, Heim Gallery to Yvonne Hackenbroch (1986)